Masa Alaya



masaal808@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/masa-al



+963953591336



https://masa-alaya.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

I have always believed that technology is our real magic which could do miracles. This is why I've been a tech enthusiast since childhood.

Currently, I am a 22 years old Software Engineering student & working as a Software Test Engineer at Source Code Company & freelance Web Developer.

I'm well-experienced in Web Development using HTML5, CSS3, JS, Python, and Vue. Js.

Also, I have good experience in Object-Oriented Programming and Algorithms using JavaScript, C++, C#, and Python.

Plus, I have solid experience in Software Testing and a good understanding of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Software Testing Life Cycle (STLC), and software testing methodologies, techniques, and technologies (JMeter, Postman, Selenium, etc.) and other different types of testing.

Skilled in writing test documentation (test scenarios, test cases, etc.) As well as analyzing and preparing resulting summary reports.

Lately, I've also started diving into advanced technologies in front-end Development.

Experience



Software Test Engineer

Source Code

Aug 2022 - Present (7 months)

I am liable for designing and implementing test procedures to ensure that software programs work as intended. I am also responsible for evaluating software using automated or manual testing methods and analyzing the results



Frontend Developer

Freelance

Nov 2021 - Present (1 year 4 months)

I am responsible for developing new user-facing features, determining the structure and design of web pages, building reusable codes, optimizing page loading times, and using a variety of markup languages to create the web pages



Tutor

Private Lessons

Oct 2019 - Sep 2021 (2 years)

I was responsible for helping students learn and understand new concepts and complete assignments. I prepare lessons by studying lesson plans, reviewing textbooks in detail to understand the topic, I will be teaching and providing additional projects if needed during a session.

Education



Syrian Virtual University SVU

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology Engineering Apr 2019 - Apr 2024

Licenses & Certifications



Youth level 1000 - Sanad Youth Foundation For Development

Skills

Front-End Development • IT Operations • Problem Solving • JavaScript • Python (Programming Language) • Responsive Web Design • PSD to HTML • HTML5 • CSS3 • Git